Yann CAYRAC

Software Engineer

CONTACT INFORMATION

2111 E. Sherwood Rd Arlington Heights, IL 60004



yann.cayrac@gmail.com





EDUCATION

Masters of Science - Computer Science and Communication Networks CPE Lyon University 2019

Bachelors of Science - Computer Science and Communication Networks
CPE Lyon University
2017

SKILLS

- ✓ React, Angular, Polymer, JavaScript
- ✓ Node.js, PHP, Java
- ✓ TS, Mocha, Chai, Git, GitLab, TDD
- ✓ MongoDB, SQL
- ✓ Docker, Jenkins, Ansible
- ✓ Linux/CentOS/Windows server admin
- ✓ UML, API, MVC, MVVM Microservices
- ✓ Agile, Scrum
- ✓ UI, UX, Needs Analysis

LANGUAGES

✓ French: Fluent Spoken & Written

ABOUT ME

I am a software engineer with many technologies and skill sets in my back pocket, as well as a creative thinker of innovative features and new ideas. I have created quality front-end and back-end applications from scratch. I have a solid grasp of unit testing, systems administration, and deployment in complex work environments. I also have experience quickly understanding existing applications and enhancing them within tight deadlines.

EXPERIENCE

Altran | Software Engineer Consultant October 2019 - February 2021

- Created predictive maintenance widgets for trucks using
 Polymer/TS and enhanced the Node.js/TS/MongoDB
 back-end platform for Volvo. Coded unit tests with Mocha
 and Chai. Deployment handled with Docker and
 OpenShift. Tight collaboration with data scientists creating
 predictive algorithms in an agile structured team. The
 components predictions provide information that directly
 reduces the number of truck mechanical failures and time
 off the road.
- Enhanced, supported, and migrated an existing finance application to the cloud for SNCF. Development in Vanilla JS on the frontend and PHP and Node JS on the backend. Deployment with Jenkins and Docker and systems administration on Windows and Ubuntu servers. The Management of this application allowed several multi million euro budget plans to be created and followed effectively.
- Created a decision support system with React and Node.js for Altran based on the analytic hierarchy process (AHP).
 The application enables decision makers to make scientific and coherent decisions using unquantifiable criteria.

EDF | Software Engineer

September 2016 - September 2019

- Created a continuous integration platform for Liferay using Jenkins and Ansible and handled RedHat system administration of the VMs. My platform allows nuclear plant technicians to access their home portal and keep it updated.
- Created a mobile-first application with Angular and Node.js connected to Planisware's API to give clear and concise planning information for nuclear plant technicians in real-time.
- Developed a continuous integration platform with Jenkins and Ansible to deploy Planisware, a tool for planning operations in nuclear plants. The platform deploys and updates planning software in 26 nuclear plants.

ISORG | C++ Developer

April 2016 - June 2016

Analyzed needs and constraints, and then developed a test platform for an light sensor assembly line.